Corbin D. Couger

(765) 891-1658 | 3831 Lake Clearwater Pl. APT 831 Indianapolis, IN 46240 | corbin.0007@yahoo.com

Summary

Data Scientist with advanced skills and background in Statistics. 3+ years of experience and a deep passion for mathematics, data, and computer science. Critical, creative, and analytical thinker solving challenging questions using advanced data analysis. Involved in different professional, educational, and personal projects to keep exploring the possibilities with Data Science and different industries.

Education & Honors

Butler University | 2017 - 2021 | Bachelors of Science: Statistics | Minor: Data Science

• College of Liberal Arts & Sciences | GPA: 3.493/4.0

Bellevue University | 2022 - Current (Graduate 2023) | Masters: Data Science

Work Experience

Myers & Stauffer | Staff Analyst

Feb. 2023 - Current | Indianapolis, IN

- Extract multiple multi-million row, 30+ variable client datasets using SQL
- Transform and clean datasets to prepare for analysis of recalculating client rates
- Analyze large datasets to find answers clients are seeking
- Prove and validate projects using data driven results

Humana Inc. | Data Analyst

May 2021 - Feb. 2023 | Indianapolis, IN

- Composed SQL queries to update & extract data from the company's databases
- Collected feedback data for multiple pilots to measure user experience & behavior
- Leveraged Power BI to create a dashboard of combined datasets to display health of company
- Researched analytical tools to help guide team for making data driven decisions after my departure

Midcontinent ISO | Summer Intern

June 2020 - Aug. 2020 | Indianapolis, IN

- Established an automated system for calculating price levels on energy, leading to improved economic margins
- Wrote Python code, utilizing Pandas, that converted raw data into useful clean data for linear regression models used to accurately predict energy prices
- Produced useful supply curves using RStudio to determine suitable data for linear regression
- Mined large company database to extract raw datasets using SQL
- Prepared and analyzed data for linear regression and hypothesis testing

Eli Lilly | Summer Replacement Student

May 2019 - Aug. 2019 | Indianapolis, IN

- Utilized JMP program to analyze control charts of maintenance operations
- Created Microsoft Excel Sheets & PowerPoints to present business cases
- Networked between Engineering & Statistic associates to collaborate on projects
- Aided in redesigning data flow for new system of analyzation

Skills

- Python
- R Programming Language
- SQL
- Tableau
- Microsoft Power BI
- Data Science
- Classification Algorithms

- Web Scraping
- Utilizing APIs
- Predictive Analytics
- Cluster Analysis
- SAS, C++, etc.
- Verbal and Written Communication
- Linear Algebra